<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE nitf SYSTEM "http://www.nitf.org/IPTC/NITF/3.3/specification/dtd/nitf-3-3.dtd">
<nitf change.date="June 10, 2005" change.time="19:30" version="-//IPTC//DTD NITF 3.3//EN">
  <head>
    <title>Alexis Smith</title>
    <meta content="1" name="publication_day_of_month"/>
    <meta content="1" name="publication_month"/>
    <meta content="1988" name="publication_year"/>
    <meta content="Friday" name="publication_day_of_week"/>
    <meta content="Weekend Desk" name="dsk"/>
    <meta content="29" name="print_page_number"/>
    <meta content="1" name="print_section"/>
    <meta content="4" name="print_column"/>
    <meta content="Arts" name="online_sections"/>
    <docdata>
      <doc-id id-string="106111"/>
      <doc.copyright holder="The New York Times" year="1988"/>
      <identified-content>
        <classifier class="indexing_service" type="descriptor">ART</classifier>
        <classifier class="indexing_service" type="descriptor">ART SHOWS</classifier>
        <classifier class="indexing_service" type="descriptor">REVIEWS</classifier>
        <classifier class="indexing_service" type="descriptor">MURALS</classifier>
        <org class="indexing_service">BROOKLYN MUSEUM</org>
        <person class="indexing_service">SMITH, ROBERTA</person>
        <person class="indexing_service">SMITH, ALEXIS (ARTIST)</person>
        <classifier class="online_producer" type="taxonomic_classifier">Top/Features/Arts</classifier>
        <classifier class="online_producer" type="taxonomic_classifier">Top/Features/Arts/Art and Design</classifier>
        <classifier class="online_producer" type="taxonomic_classifier">Top/Features/Travel/Guides/Activities and Interests/Art</classifier>
        <classifier class="online_producer" type="general_descriptor">Art</classifier>
      </identified-content>
    </docdata>
    <pubdata date.publication="19880101T000000" ex-ref="http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=940DE7DB1639F932A35752C0A96E948260" item-length="320" name="The New York Times" unit-of-measure="word"/>
  </head>
  <body>
    <body.head>
      <hedline>
        <hl1>Alexis Smith</hl1>
      </hedline>
    </body.head>
    <body.content>
      <block class="lead_paragraph">
        <p>LEAD:  The Brooklyn Museum 200 Eastern Parkway Through Jan. 11 Alexis Smith is a California artist who emerged in the mid-1970's as part of the narrative or story-art phenomenon, a more talkative, less hermetic branch of Conceptual art. Ms. Smith's metier is a collage-like installation that, using film stills, bits of printed matter, small found objects and quotations from fiction, tells tales in visual terms.</p>
      </block>
      <block class="full_text">
        <p>LEAD:  The Brooklyn Museum 200 Eastern Parkway Through Jan. 11 Alexis Smith is a California artist who emerged in the mid-1970's as part of the narrative or story-art phenomenon, a more talkative, less hermetic branch of Conceptual art. Ms. Smith's metier is a collage-like installation that, using film stills, bits of printed matter, small found objects and quotations from fiction, tells tales in visual terms.</p>
        <p>The Brooklyn Museum 200 Eastern Parkway Through Jan. 11 Alexis Smith is a California artist who emerged in the mid-1970's as part of the narrative or story-art phenomenon, a more talkative, less hermetic branch of Conceptual art. Ms. Smith's metier is a collage-like installation that, using film stills, bits of printed matter, small found objects and quotations from fiction, tells tales in visual terms. In Ms. Smith's latest effort, a mural titled ''Same Old Paradise'' executed specifically for the enormous wall in the lobby of the Brooklyn Museum, she moves to the big scale of the movie screen and highway billboard.</p>
        <p>''Same Old Paradise'' takes on the myth of westward expansion, 1930's version, when the Depression and the Dust Bowl sent many Americans to California. The work's inspiration is Jack Kerouac's ''On the Road,'' whose hero is named Sal Paradise. Its main image shows the open road as it winds through acres of beautiful orange trees.</p>
        <p>Along the picture's lower edge, the road turns into a huge twisting snake. To the right of the snake, six quotes from Kerouac's novel are matched up with images from advertising. They are framed in faded green wood that seems straight out of a roadside diner. Sometimes a tarnished three-dimensional object is added. In the third frame an image of a denim-jacketed elbow is supplemented by an armrest from the door of an old car and the sentence, from Kerouac, ''I was rushing through the world without a chance to see it.'' The next frame is dominated by a road map of Colorado, Denver being the first main stop on Sal Paradise's westward trip.</p>
        <p>Ms. Smith's talent for condensing narrative, and for matching up word and image with a minimum of fuss and a maximum of resonance, continues unabated. The new large format reduces the personal, handmade element of her art, but what the artist has lost in ambiance she has gained in accessibility and impact.</p>
      </block>
    </body.content>
  </body>
</nitf>
